We had a period of extraordinary change
in our space like extraordinary
transformation. So we had a new
administration which brought in a new
SEC. We got guidance from DFTC SEC. All
of a sudden 2.0 is being rolled back. It
was being investigated. We had all the
pieces for institutional participation.
I think that we have hit a point where
much of traditional finance is beginning
to understand and see the functionality
that has developed in crypto markets
that would be phenomenal to introduce to
traditional markets. I mean, think about
the way mainstream people are getting
excited about perks, right? They want to
get up to speed. It's been like one sort
of inbound, hey, somebody from a board
called and they want to know if you can
come do a teaching on tokenization. And
I have been surprised by how much the
sort of pace picked up very very
quickly.
>> Hi, I'm Ralph Pal and welcome to my
show, The Journeyman. That journey is
that journey of understanding at the
nexus of macro crypto and the
exponential age of technology.
For me, one of the things I'm lucky with
is, you know, I came out of the
investment banking, institutional, hedge
fund space, and I know a lot of people
in that space and a lot of people trust
Real Vision and myself with their
stories because we don't sensationalize
it. We ask them proper questions, and we
really want to find out what's going on.
And they come to also find out how
people think about the world and where
it's going. So, this time is a new guest
for me, Blue. She's coming in from Tro
Price and she runs crypto there. She
also has a institutional background and
a hedge fund background. So we speak the
same language. We have the same kind of
understanding. And so I really wanted to
pick her brains on what she's seeing
from the institutional perspective,
markets in general, and how she can
apply her own trading past to these
markets. It's going to be a fascinating
conversation. Enjoy.
Join me, Ral Pal, as I go on a journey
of discovery through the macro, crypto,
and exponential age landscapes. In the
journey, man, I talk to the smartest
people in the world so we can all become
smarter together.
Blue, fantastic to have you on Real
Vision.
>> Thanks for having me. Great to be here.
>> So, give me as ever. I love everybody's
journey into this crazy space. How the
hell did you get here? Give me your
story.
>> So, I am trained as an economist um and
had always done emerging markets um
fixed income rates FX. I was at Lehman
uh in London in 2008 when we went
bankrupt.
>> Oh, wow.
>> Uh yeah. And then I went to Elliot where
I did like liquid emerging markets,
which is probably not everyone else's
version of liquid. Um and and had always
just primarily done distressed debt. um
and a lot of sovereigns. Uh and in 2017,
I was uh living in Brazil. My husband
was the deputy governor of the central
bank there. So, we moved to Brazil and I
was working in private equity,
distressed private equity. And I had a
friend who said, "Oh, if you if you need
to be sending money back to the States,
the best way to do it is since you're
dual resident, you should do it using
Bitcoin and then you can go hedge your
exposure."
Uh, and I did that. I hit Bloomberg mid
and it took 60 minutes and I didn't have
to go to a towel in person. It didn't
take 5 days. I didn't, you know, um, see
those kinds of spreads and fees. Uh, and
the light just went off and I said, "Oh
my, why isn't everyone doing this?" Um,
and so that's how I got into crypto. and
uh and coming from emerging markets debt
like I I know what a sovereign balance
sheet should look like and I know what a
sovereign balance sheet shouldn't look
like and uh and so I resigned from a top
10 global private equity fund to go
launch a market neutral crypto fund in
2018 and that's haven't looked back
>> and also I found there's a lot of um EM
FX traders and option traders who've
moved to crypto because they understand
gap risk ill liquidity volatility
information asymmetry all skew I mean
all of it right it's a very similar
skill set to some of that stuff
>> yeah it's interesting because you get
people from all different like finance
backgrounds so like you got the equities
guys and they look at it a certain way
and then you got the commodities guys
and they're like they make fantastic
traders in this space um but I always I
always think that the people who pick it
up the fastest are like our FX guys.
>> Yeah, that's right. And to think of it
as a currency is pretty useful. And as
you said, the commodity guys because
they also have to deal with volatility
and that kind of stuff. It kind of works
for them. But why the stupid idea of a
market neutral fund? I mean, that was
quite a big mix from what you were doing
to that. And what kind of trades were
you doing then back then?
>> Yeah. So, um, I always joke I'm like the
only person in crypto from the class of
2017 who's not either retired or in
jail. Um but uh but um but basically uh
it was
sort of cross exchange ARB. It was cross
exchange ARB. It was cross exchange ARB.
Um and then basis um which back then the
spreads were so big that you could drive
a truck through them, right? Uh and this
is before you could do onshore basis and
and we were registered in Brazil and
with the CBM. Um, but why market
neutral? Um, I started out as somewhat
of a crypto skeptic. Um, and I I liked
that
crypto is the first like when you look
at crypto assets, when you look at
tokens, they are the very first truly
100% fungeable spot commodities that can
be traded simultaneously anywhere in the
world. Wheat, well, there's there's
Ukrainian red wheat and there's Kansas
and you right and same with oil. you get
these very small there. I actually think
of crypto market neutral as probably the
only true like market neutral out there
because the assets are fungeible. Um and
so even though I had only ever done the
most directional things like almost
activist restructuring that you could
do, I actually really liked being able
to do this market neutral. Um and then
made the transition to Tro once I felt
like the space had become robust enough,
we had enough chains that you could do
true directional like you could model,
you could build um you could
really take different views on on chains
and tokens um which up until then have
been a little bit like throwing darts at
a board to some extent you know.
>> Yeah. And so Tro what did you come on to
do and what are you doing now? So I
joined to build out all of the digital
assets business. So I started we had no
infrastructure. Um and so I built the
entire sort of endtoend um we have an
entirely cryptonnative setup. We don't
use any two row existing systems except
for Microsoft Outlook. Uh so we use so
we do we have the same sort of operating
engine and endto-end experience um as
you would expect from a from a totally
cryptonative um outfit. And so built all
of that and then uh by 2023 we were
trading 20 plus tokens internally in a
portfolio.
but there just wasn't a regulatory
framework or a path to bringing
something to market for retail. Um, and
that really only came into came into
play in the way that we needed it to to
be able to do active investing, active
multi-token investing, you know,
probably a year ago with the generic
listing standards was a big
breakthrough.
>> And what when you first joined Turo,
what was the attitude there? Were you
kind of stuck in the closet and hidden
away and like don't talk to these
people, they're bad people. I mean, how
was it? What was the attitude? Because
it's different at different firms.
>> It is. Um, so I my first day at TERO was
like July 31st, 2022.
So that that's like six, eight weeks
before the FTX debacle began, right? And
I remember I remember the very first
question that I got in an all hands
meeting when I sort of did the
introduction and then there was silence
afterwards and then someone raised their
hand and they said isn't bitcoin just
for drug dealers and I was like so it's
you know um that's not really the case
anymore and uh it's actually more
transparent to be able to trace things
on chain and it's it's not that
effective a tool for criminal activity
because you can see everywhere that your
token went. Um, but I have to say the
thing that amazed me the most was the
open-mindedness
of people at Tro. So, it's like it's a
very researchoriented shop. And so, when
you sit down and you sort of they are
willing to be, you know, sit there and
have a conversation and you lay out the
case for, you know, this is what Salana
does, this is the case for Bitcoin, this
is what Hyperlid does. People will
follow you through that journey. And if
you lay the case out and you support it
with evidence, the guy who asked me if
Bitcoin was for drug dealers, um, is the
holder of tokens, our new ETF, and is
like one of the biggest proponents and
keeps asking me when we're going to
bring all these different things on
chain. So like there was a willingness
to learn and have an open-mindedness to
like really think about um changing a
viewpoint, right? they weren't biased
and that was really important
>> and actually very useful time for you to
be setting up when things are blowing
up. A you've lived that before a hundred
times because you understand distress
assets, you understand how it works. You
know your job has been essentially to
capture those opportunities but also
building your risk systems and your
custody systems. It's super useful to
say like this is why we need kind of
best-in-class in what we do because
these are the kinds of crazy that
happens in these markets. Yeah. And and
I had already sort of laid out the
architecture for what we were going to
do and how we were going to be treated
and and all the different pieces and I
was able to go my first introduction to
the equities Monday morning meeting was
the the Monday after FTX and they said
can you can you come in and explain what
happened um and I was able to say based
on the architecture that we've already
presented we would have had we obviously
would have had price market exposure to
like the drop in value of assets but we
would have had zero counterparty
exposure or vendor exposure.
um even through January, even through
everything we saw. that daisy chain of
of bankruptcies and stuff through um
through December, January and that was
really important and they they say build
in a bare market and this was build in a
bare market and Tro stuck it out right a
lot of what we see in every other cycle
as institutions like you remember
January 2018 I think the I think the
Goldman shut their entire desk right um
so you would have things like that those
cycles and
Tro didn't blink they just said you know
keep building keep And that's an
incredibly
it's an incredibly unusual thing to be
in a place where they are willing to
support the platform.
>> It's bizarre that firms that are cont
considered sort of conservative Fidelity
Tro
have actually been the people who stuck
it through. Goldman, JP Morgan,
everybody else kind of built a business,
pulled the plug. Built a business,
pulled the plug. I mean, incredible.
>> Yeah. I think I think we should cut the
banks a little bit of slack in that they
are the regulatory environment in the US
became really hostile and it was very
much directed towards banks um and asset
managers still had a lot of freedom and
autonomy to continue to build in the
space and do things um and it became an
incredibly restrictive environment for
banks um for broker dealers you know in
the US
>> the other thing that I've observed about
risk that you talk about counterparty
risk
I think the space doesn't have enough
financial people who've been through
this before and they don't understand
that it's not necessarily your
counterparty that's the problem. It's
their counterparty that's the problem.
>> Yeah. I think that um
>> and that's in DeFi particularly you see
this all the time is people don't
understand that yeah sure you know it
looks like your margins everything get
sorted out in one go but systemic
failure people don't understand it.
>> Yeah. I I think that's absolutely true.
I think we very much saw that post FTX.
I think that people didn't understand
and did have visibility onto the like
sort of a look through onto the type of
exposure that each entity had to all the
other entities, right? Um and that it
was a very small world of people lending
to each other.
>> I mean, I had exactly this with
long-term capital when I was at Goldman
and they blew up. Um
basically everybody's biggest client was
the same client. And in this time
around, everybody's biggest client was
Three Arrows Capital and nobody knew.
>> Exactly. And I think um
I think that we I feel like a lot of
places didn't have proper risk managers,
like they hadn't brought someone in who
had done it. Um and uh and someone who
had been through like a real serious
everybody heads for the door at the same
time crisis, right? Because when we
think about liquidity is great, but if
nobody, you know, but it correlation
goes to one and the door gets really
small on the way out when you have a
crisis and you see it in EM, you see it
to a lesser extent in equity markets,
but like you see it in in EM and in
macro and you saw it in long-term
capital management, right? Um and and
when you have a massive system that in
large part a big portion of it is retail
operating on auto liquidation.
It just like it adds a bunch of
surprises to the mix, right? Like it's
like surprise, guess what? Guess what
happened? You're not long. Like um so uh
you know I I think that I think that
people learned an incredible amount from
what happened post FTX.
What why do you think crypto's been
struggling with attracting liquidity in
this environment recently? It kind of
part of it was
1010. Whatever happened in October that
left some residual scarring on the
business overall, but since then it's
never really captured any of the upside
that it normally would have captured in
this kind of macro environment. I think
there's a couple things. One thing that
still kind of gets under my skin and
bothers me is that I don't feel like we
really understand as a community what
happened 10 10 like I don't I I've heard
many sort of expost explanations
because people always look for a reason
and none of them have
I don't feel like I I've heard something
where I was like oh okay that was it
that makes sense to me at the same time
I think many people were waiting based
from past experiences, past cycles.
We're waiting for a lot of bodies to
flow to the service and they didn't,
right? So I and I and I think that we're
far enough along that that really is the
case. I think people were hurt. I think
people, you know, funds were down,
probably had a lot of withdrawals, but
um it it didn't become this sort of um
mass of bodies rising to the surface,
which I think says a lot about the the
maturity of the way that people and what
people learned from the last time
around. When we think about why crypto
has been struggling so much um sort of
since since the fall um I think it's a
couple things. I think we had a period
of extraordinary change in our space
like extraordinary transformation. So we
had a new administration which brought
in a new SEC. We got guidance from CFTC
SEC. All of a sudden 2.0 was being
rolled back. It was being investigated.
um we had all the pieces for
institutional participation. Um many
institutions started to understand it
and and sort of get what was going to be
happening in terms of tokenization or
onchain finance, however you want to say
it. Um but we had it, you know,
basically from this from the launch of
the first Bitcoin ETFs until sort of
through last summer, we were on like a
sugar high. We had like non-stop great
news. Every time we turned around,
something unprecedented was happening in
crypto, right? It was this person's
doing this or this, you know, um this
rule has been, you know, rolled out. We
got this type of guidance. Um
and I think that it's impossible to
sustain that type of constant
transformational um news flow. Uh and
and so I think that's part of what
happened was like we kind of came down
off the sugar high. And I think that to
a certain extent uh
even though most people in crypto I
think have a very good sense of the
intersection
and the potential between crypto and AI,
I think that for your marginal crypto
buyer that AI sucked a lot of air out of
the room. And um when we were watching
sort of the SpaceX IPO, I think that
internally we were sort of watching very
carefully what was happening. He was
like, "Yeah, I think the marginal buyer
of the SpaceX IPO is like a Salana
holder. I absolutely think that like
that's a guy who's going to Right."
>> Well, you can even see it on crypto
Twitter. The people who used to be pure
crypto people are now AI and crypto
people or completely move to AI because
it gets attention. You can make money
and people in the end are you know
they'll just choose where they can go to
make money. Yeah. That's where capsule
goes always.
>> Yeah. And I but I also think it's been
for that there's like I do think there's
a whole subset of people who see the I
hate this word but the synergy between
the relationship between AI and crypto
like machines can't use real American
dollars like that's not on the table. Um
and
that's like kind of the tip of the
iceberg. Um but I think that especially
for those marginal buyers when they're
thinking about you know adding risk high
growth techreated risk they have been
doing that in AI on the equity side
rather than you know rather than in
crypto the past year. Yeah, I just for
some reason, you know, the liquidity mix
wasn't good enough, I think, to have
excess
investment capital. So, um, you know, I
look at sort of excess liquidity, which
is liquidity growth above GDP growth and
it hasn't been very strong. So any
liquidity that's come into the market
goes to the one focus of attention which
has been AI which has been given a great
return and we just not had that
liquidity cycle and and you know price
begets price and it brings in volume and
everything else and you know so I think
it's been an issue of that but when I
step back and you look what's happening
with the rise of stable coins and how
fast it's growing the small but but
growing RWA bucket that's coming and
Then the very nent but gigantic
um agentic
you know payments and finance systems
that are coming i.e. the TAM of of
crypto has gone from 8 billion people to
infinite agents.
>> Yeah I think um
>> so the underlying is really strong
but the activity levels because retail
is not really there is not great yet.
every institutional player now is
building something. They have an
opinion. They want to do something. So,
it's all there. It's all in place to
happen.
>> I think so. I also um
I also think that the sort of the most
many of the most popular or the broadest
or most mainstream like AI sort of
equity plays are still largely around
the narrative is very much around core
infrastructure. I don't think people
have gotten to
the potential or the application
uh in the same way and I I think that
follows. Um but I think it's very much
about infrastructure uh and sort of
hardware still. Um and I think and I
think there's you know it's so new that
I think there's a lot of people who
don't understand yet what it means and
so they're sort of doing that thing.
It's like the taxi driver told me to buy
Nvidia. like it's that sort of top layer
of things and you have to let it mature
>> at which point that sort of interplay
between those things will become much
more clear. I think on the crypto call
it the crypto side and this is one of
the things that I always find super
interesting. It kind of puzzles me is
sitting in the institutional seat that I
sit in. I obviously there's a lot of
tokenization discussion and then there's
like the crypto investing side and the
extent to which
when I am having sort of industry
trodify conversations around
tokenization the extent to which people
are still separating
crypto and tokenization
really surprises me. We think that
there's going to be call it a trillion,
call it five trillion, whatever your
number is on stable coins. But like
>> that's block space, right? Like so where
where do we like to me it's just that's
like an obvious connection.
>> Well, because I think we we made a
mistake because how we bootstrap Yeah.
We me'd
>> a$ two half trillion dollar industry
into existence.
>> Yeah.
>> By
being sort of divisive. It's like mine
versus yours. All of this stuff built
the network effects that built this
space, but it ended up leaving a
toxicity that people didn't like
cryptocurrency but thought blockchain
was a great technology. You're like
actually one is just the payment rail
for the use of the block space.
>> Exactly. Yeah. and and Tradfi is going
to and has to a large extent
particularly on the asset management
side going to go through
like a journey where they they begin to
understand that
what we all learned in like in previous
cycles which is why different
blockchains are suited for different
things and why interoperability is
absolutely key like that this is needs
to be a fully interoperable space that a
a real estate land grab walled garden
doesn't work. It doesn't sustain it.
>> Do you think we're running into problems
with this with the stable coin market?
Because we're seeing this coalition of
people on sort of their own sort of
permission chains, then we're seeing the
open- source ones. Then we're seeing it
multi-chain and it's like I'm looking at
this thinking this is a mess cuz it's
not very easy to send you a dollar which
was the whole idea because we're kind of
losing the interoperability because
people are trying to capture market
share without realizing you'll all have
market share just let it grow.
>> Exactly. Um, and also without realizing
that
a difficult UX UI is is like the biggest
hurdle to adoption. If we make this
>> us crypto people are kings of queens of
that. We've made the worst UX and UI in
existence and we still have it.
>> I know. I that I I like it. I'd say
like, you know, like I, you know, I
slept till 3:00 in the morning on GitHub
like trying to figure out like Discord
trying to figure out how to get that $20
back that I like sent here by accident
and I've just like now abandoned it.
It's like no, we're not scaling like
this. People regular people will not
participate and do this. Um, like it's
going to be a real issue with stable
coins. We have to if if we're saying
it's we say to people like this is
amazing like you could just boom like
you know pay it needs to feel like that
for them and we need to make it like
that and I think that we will get there.
Um, I always, and this is like totally
dating myself, but I feel like the way
that I look at stable coins right now
and the phase that we're in is that it's
a lot like when we like went from cable
to screen streaming and it was like
cable, it was like you you just turn on
the TV and you could go through the
channels and it had a menu and you could
see what was on and you could, you know,
it was like super user friendly. Um, and
then we went to super fragmented
streaming and now it's like there'll be
a show and I want to watch it and I
can't remember which of the 12 streaming
services like and I'm like oh but I
canceled that but now I like now I need
to sign back up for it because now it
moves streaming services and that's what
stable coins are like right now. That's
not going to help us
grow. And I think that and I think to a
large extent the you know the winner is
going to be the person who is able to
abstract away the back end and bridging
and all of the things that crypto people
are willing to do that the average
consumer is not. And that's how you're
going to you know sort of become that
market leader.
>> Yeah. I mean I've talked about this is
like I don't know what computer you're
on, what Wi-Fi network you're on, what
um
>> operating system you're running. It
doesn't matter. It just works. If I
click, you know, open on the video and
and you pop up and you don't know my
end, it's like it needs to be that
that's interoperable.
>> Yeah. And it needs to be seamless. For
the most part, crypto has matured to a
point where everybody who's going to get
here through code is already here.
Everybody who is going to get here
through like sort of hardcore attack,
they're already here. Um, and they're
willing to brave the, you know, Discord
at 2 o'clock in the morning, whatever it
is. Um, I totally get that. I'm not your
typical crypto demographic. I'm okay
with that. But, um,
I'm a middle-aged mom of three and I'm
pretty willing to show up and and try
things. So, like I run my entire family
cell phone plan. We moved it all to
Helium. Like, you know, I have a
Hivemapper and then Opair's car. Like,
the whole thing. I'm about as scripted
word as you get for, you know, Among the
Mom set. Um, and
you're not going to find that with the
rest of the people. And so we are not
making products,
products, apps, utility, interface that
brings the marginal non- tech
hardcore tech person in like there is no
path to adoption.
>> No. No. because in the end it should be
the rails for the entire financial
system and a bunch of other things like
identity and you know provenence and
there's a whole bunch of things that
we've kind of even stalled on right now
because nobody's really talking about
identity properly with all of the AI
going on it should be top of mind people
have stopped with the whole idea of web
3 the readr write own idea that's
stalled as well
>> yeah um it's
>> just a little sad I like I hope it picks
back
But um but yeah, no, we have s like we
saw in a lot of those things. Um
identity and often the way that I
explain it internally is blockchain is
not great for everything. It's not
perfect for everything. Um there are
plenty of things that can and should be
done on a database, right? Yeah,
>> blockchain is fantastic for anything
that is complex, difficult
um or needs to be securely moved,
transferred and represented across
internal and external parties, right?
And that's a huge swath of things like
the identity piece um is critical and
like yeah I've become very I become
increasingly concerned about a I just
become more and more concerned about AI
pretty much every day but um but I I
just don't understand how we're not more
you know more focused on identity.
I I went through this
>> realization what was coming in 2021 and
I got together
some of the kind of senior folks at
Amazon
Meta
um LinkedIn Microsoft which is LinkedIn
as well um who else a whole bunch of
them and I I got them all on the call
and said listen you're all kind of
working on the crypto side in those ind
in those bit Google as well and um I
said listen AI is coming. We desperately
need digital ID and it needs to be
onchain. It needs to have the
provenence. All of that they said
absolutely. I said because what is going
to happen is we're going to have fake
content looking like me doing stuff that
I've not sanctioned and it's going to be
the wild west. It's going to be and you
you guys are going to get sued like the
banks did after 2008 and you'll be sued
for a decade over this. And they're like
yes. And I said, "So, let's get together
and build a common standard." And they
said, "We'd love to, but we're never
going to agree each other's credentials.
They don't want interoperability."
So, Microsoft was saying, "We're not
going to take Amazon's
credentialization."
And I'm like, "Can you not agree
something?" No. So, I said, "Do you
understand where this leads is you will
end up getting sued?" And they're like,
"Yeah."
>> Yeah. I I mean, what that's really
incredible. Um and that's kind of
>> but not surprising right
>> I will not surprising but I will add
that to the list of other things that
concern me right this growing list um
but I also think it concerns me that I
think many regular people who who are
outside this industry or outside AI or
maybe even outside finance um are not
deeply and profoundly concerned about
AI. I feel like people I Yeah, I feel
like the general public hasn't gotten to
the point where they know to sue yet.
>> They just haven't no clue of how far
this has gone and how how urgently
important is. And government's too slow
for for AI. I mean, this is I mean, we
were used to metaf's law in crypto which
was fast
um you know to go through that
exponential curve is quite something.
This is that squared. It's Reed's law.
The first example doesn't appear in
biology. It's happening in AI. I mean,
it's staggering. And so, no government
can keep up with this.
>> No. Especially not our government, not
the US government. Um, but I Yeah, I
think it's it's a little terrifying. Um,
I I one of my co-portfolio managers
who's like the lead analyst. It's It's
good. We really balance each other out,
but his he has a masters in AI and and
probably every fourth phone call, you
know, every fourth call, we wind up like
steering off into AI. And then I'm like
I like stop. We have to like we have to
put a lid on it because I'm not going to
be able to sleep tonight and I'm just
going to be terrified about this like
end of days and um
you know and we saw the breakout. We saw
that we saw the rogue attack and I was
like so what you're saying is the the AI
broke out broke out in order to cheat on
its homework. I was like, "So tell me AI
is like a teenager without telling me
it's a teenager." But it's um
the element of self-reporting that is
required
by the AI firms like like it's they
share with us. Okay, this has happened.
You know, some something's escaped the
lab
and and the fact that it's like sort of
a voluntary self-reporting. Well, how
else you going to do it? It's moving too
fast.
>> I mean, you see the new frontier model
>> every two weeks right now.
>> Yeah.
>> And from my measurements compounding um
intelligence is compounding.
Uh it's like doubling every five months.
Uh the efficiency of intelligence
output, there's no way. We've never
dealt with anything like this. I mean,
the only way to do it is have a holy
moment. Guys, guys, this is what's
happened to us, which is what they're
doing. Elon spoke about this. I It was
last week. He's like, what are we
supposed to do here? All we can do is is
kind of tell each other we've got a
problem with something. Tell the US
government and say, listen, or we've
got, and you're seeing Open AI doing it
now. And anthropically before is like,
okay, we've got a new class of model.
This is a lot more powerful. You guys
need to check it out first. And in the
end, the US government will get to use
it for a month or three months first to
use it for their own needs and then you
release the model.
>> Yeah. I I mean I think it just
I but I I think that we should all be
I'm going to sound like a crazy person.
We should all be very suspicious, right?
That that it is all sort of
self-reported and the assumption is that
they're reporting things that are like
they're letting people know when
something important has happened and
something escaped the lab, right? Um,
but there's a huge element of trust
there that I don't I personally am don't
really have at this point. Um, and I so
I you know and I don't I don't know that
there's a solution. I don't I don't
think there's any way to successfully or
coherently or intelligently regulate it
at a government level. I mean I just
don't think that that's a true option in
a feasible way.
>> And there's so much game theory at play
here. here. I mean, don't forget
anthropic is the largest fastest scaling
of revenues in any company in human
history.
The game is so big and then it's the
game of the US versus China that it
becomes when I look at it from sort of
game theory perspectives impossible to
stop.
>> And it's a horrible outcome from a game
theory perspective. Like it it's getting
to the worst possible place and as
quickly as humanly as quickly as
possible by machine, right? It's that
that combination. So, knowing in like a
game theory context, it's a terrifying
outcome, which is one of the things that
keeps me up at night. Um, but uh, you
know, I so I I just um I think I
selectively like choose to put my
blinders back on and like go back to my
like go back to my world because other
you know what else what else do you do?
>> I'm the opposite. I just kind of throw
myself into it and say, "Well, we're
along for the ride. It's going to
happen. There's nothing I or you or any
government or anybody can do about this.
Even Elon said, he said, "I tried. I
gave up. I just joined it." And it's
like
the So this is the most extraordinary
time in human history to be alive. We've
birthed intelligence that is beyond our
own. And we're going to put
AGI
into physical form into robots.
>> Yes. And we are not ready for this
because we're going to have smarter,
stronger, faster, cheaper
intelligence carriers with dexterity
and they're going to be scalable beyond
anything we understand
and that's three years away
>> and no ethical no ethical boundaries,
right? Um like optimizing without ethics
is a terrifying idea. I mean, that's the
piece that scares me, right? I mean, if
if you could if there was a way to
include the
>> ethics. I mean, without going off the
deep end of all of this, what are our
ethics versus Chinese ethics versus
somebody else's ethics?
What ethics are these things going to
have themselves?
The point being, my my point being is
I think all layers of intelligence are
built upon each other and they you need
a symbiosis. Like we if we destroy the
planet, which is the layer of
intelligence beneath us, we're dead and
if AI kills us, it's dead
because you need the kind of compute of
all the other layers. It's a longer
conversation about this stuff, but it is
not going to kill us. Now, I one of the
things um I remember sort of at the
fairly early on during the Iran
conflict, there was a um there was a an
Imperial War College um study that was
released on like AI across models
participating in war games
like nine out of 10 they like go nuclear
like they event like and they get there
within like three or four steps. that's
like becomes the optimal outcome is
always they just like go straight for
the nuclear weapons. Um and it was
across models. Um and and then even when
you tried to input like you know this is
bad for humans like like you would kill
you know x many innocent people
civilians that no didn't matter. And
that to me is like is is that piece that
you can't
to me it's still a leap of faith that we
don't we don't wind up killing off the
intelligence layer underneath us which
is a very like dark thing to say I
think. So sorry pup.
>> So a quick break in your regular
programming. If you're serious about
your future grab my free report called
prepare for 2030. I think you've got 5
years to make as much money as possible
and this guide will help you navigate
what's coming. The link is in the
description. Download it now.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I don't know. I just I'm
much more optimistic about the whole
thing.
>> Whilst I while I see the risks, I think
normally the good outcome is the one
that prevails.
>> Humans are pretty messy creatures
anyway. Pretty messy compute. We like
killing each other. We like taking each
other's resources. We do all sorts of
weird things anyway, which most other
animals don't do, but we do.
It's
>> I mean I um
>> but we haven't managed to destroy
everything is the point we could
>> correct. I was at Leman during the
bankruptcy and then I went on to do
distressed debt and I come from like a
debt like a fixed income debt background
not an equity equity people are like
it's going to be okay look let's all
look on the upside it'll be fantastic
you know like everybody will have lots
of extra time because the AI is doing
your work and I'm like the machines are
going to kill us all that's like the
fixed income that's like where fixed
income people go and especially
distressed people are like you know like
it's like Armageddon is where you go
>> well Um,
>> I was the same in in macro. I made all
of my money in bare markets and I had to
retrain my entire thinking process when
I realized that this this kind of
technological trend because I kind of
scoffed at NASDAQ and stuff and like,
oh, these guys are all kind of they're
smoking the hopium. And then after a
while, I realized that I was so wrong
and that I actually had to flip my
entire mindset from looking for crashes
to looking for buying opportunities and
looking forward to when the market fell.
Uh it was hard.
>> Exactly. Exactly. I um I had a CIO um
Elliot and he used to always say the
most expensive thing you can be in our
business is rigid.
And it's like it's so true. like you
have to be able to sort of take the
opposite view. You need to be able to
push yourself. You cannot get wedded um
to a position where you're a position or
viewpoint or an outlook where you just
can't like it's just too expensive to be
rigid, right? Um that's the most
important lesson I think that like I
learned in that process. So when you're
looking at out across crypto markets
which have been kind of low volatility
sort of boring sideways markets for a
while now
where are we where's the opportunity?
So I think um
>> on the investing side, not the building
side. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think I very much like uh and
continue to see a lot of opportunity uh
in I'm going to call it onchain finance
onchain rwa/to tokenizosation onchain
finance like the whole umbrella.
>> Yeah. Um and
and this is also actually I think part
of one of the reasons that markets
haven't been great the past year is I
think that we told told people for ages
institutions are coming institutions are
coming everybody's going to tokenize
everything institutions are coming and
then we said oh my god the institutions
are here because we got like you know
big announcements people are doing this
people are doing that and and they
haven't I think the average sort of
investor or the person in the crypto
market has not seen that translate into
like increased network code increase,
right? Um, which is tragically move
super slow. Like institutions are here
and institutions are building. We're
just not fast, right? Um, and and crypto
markets are not necessarily that
patient. Um, and I think they've not
known for their patience. They've um and
so we haven't seen it translate. Um, but
it is so clear to me the extent to which
things are moving on chain. So all
anybody wants to talk about is how we're
getting to 247 trading in like US
equities. And guess what? Like you know
how that's going to happen? It's got to
be on chain because
of blockchain. People don't understand
that the DTCC
clears I don't know a quadrillion two
quadrillion stupid numbers. This is
what's coming for Blockspace
is all of this
>> and there's like there's a lot of work
to be done, right? Like these are these
are all sort of like people are figuring
out the pilots and like the you know
there's it's a slower process. Um
especially when we talk about sort of
functioning mainstream traditional
markets being able to transition on
chain everything has to be done as like
a sidec car as a pilot because you can't
mess with the stuff that actually works
and like literally powers the global
economy. So you can't tinker with it
while it's in action. So it's got to be
over here and separate and you have a
bunch of firms again much like your
example of all of those like big tech
firms they have to come together and you
have to agree industry standards right
so you have you know dozens of broker
dealers you have dozens of asset
managers you have inter right you have
so many different people who have to
come together and agree on
what that industry standard looks like
and you know how we sort of do that
collectively um in order to transition
Um and so it's it's not going to be fast
and it is not going to be incremental.
It will be experimental
and then sort of all at once but between
that so it's like payments tokenization
like chain suited for for tokenization.
I love, you know, hyperlquid. Um I think
the number of phone calls that I've
gotten from sort of traditional hedge
fund managers or CIOS are saying like,
"Oh, yeah, like, oh, I hadn't spoken to
them in six months." And they're like,
"Hey, so I want watching this hype. What
do you think about this hype stuff?" You
know? Um so I I think that we have hit a
point where much of traditional finance
is beginning to understand and see the
functionality that has developed in
crypto markets that would be phenomenal
to introduce to traditional markets. I
mean, think about think about the way
mainstream people are getting excited
about perks, right? Think about the way,
right? So, all of these like prediction
markets. Um, and
>> I mean, that's one good thing is I've
seen
>> to see the rate of um innovation and
speed of adoption that Robin Hood has
been doing. Vlad has done astonishing
job there. Um, astonishing how fast
they're moving and that's pushing
everybody else to move faster. It's
pushing Coinbase to try and move faster
because they're pretty slow for a what
should be a more nimble organization.
Um, and then it's causing others to as
well, which is good. And that was came
from Vlad is obviously very aware of
hype and everything else. But yeah, it's
coming, but it's coming from retail
again.
>> It is. And I I'm a huge fan of Robin
Hood and they what is fascinating is
they are transforming like both sides of
the aisle. So like they're coming like
they're coming for everybody, right? So
like they're they're coming for
traditional Yeah. for your traditional
platforms. They're coming for like
they're coming for your crypto side. So
they are applying pressure on both sides
and have
>> have accelerated movement on on both
sides um on the Trady side and on like
the sort of fintech crypto side
>> and the wealth management side and the
asset management all at the same time.
It's like
>> Yeah. and and their their customer base
is maturing, right? So, they're starting
to move into like, okay, well, how do we
offer services for people who are now,
you know, maybe married and have kids or
like are actually thinking about
retirement. And so, they are expanding
into that territory historically very
much dominated by more traditional shops
um and more traditional platforms. Um,
and like when you look at the numbers,
um, like one of the things that's just
absolutely amazing and it's consistent
study after study after study is the way
that the demographics split on sort of
who has traditional brokerage accounts
and who has like a fintech, right, app
um, account. And as you skew younger or
more people like their first experience
is digital, they hold like more digital
assets than they do um, you know, mutual
funds. um all of these different things.
Um and and it's been really interesting
to see that
demographic component sort of play out
very much through Robin Hood and I think
that the pressure it's putting on the
rest of the industry in all directions
is fantastic for the industry in terms
of evolving. And what is it? What signal
do you take from that from what you
should be doing at TRO? You know,
because you have retail, you have
institutional products, you have all of
the things. What signal do you get from
all of this that you need to to do?
Because on one hand, you're cryptonative
and you'll want to move faster. The
other hand, it's quite difficult to
move, but there's product innovation can
come. There's a lot of kind of
complexity in this. it is um I think
it's so we have um we're also sort of in
the midst of of
really being thoughtful about how we
approach tokenization
um and up until now so for the first
several years when you're like 28 2018
2019 like sort of all the way through
probably last year um the the technology
continued to get faster more efficient
cheaper So essentially you could now
tokenize something what would have cost
you I don't $15 million a 100 people in
two and a half years to do four years
ago you can I always do it's like a
build-a- bear workshop or whatever and
it's like you can go to securitize you
be like boop boop boop boop boop and
this chain and it does this and boop
boop and out pops the tokenized fund. So
tokenization as a service has really
advanced
which makes it a really interesting
question which is why are you tokenizing
what you're tokenizing like who are you
trying to reach? What do they want? It
is a tool and so it is much more about
thinking through who you are trying to
reach and the right type of product for
them rather than saying like oh it's
like a huge it's not an ops
conversation. It's not a tech
conversation. It's a business strategy
conversation.
Um, and
the other piece is is that
much of the legacy sort of what is the
bulk of business now and then ultimately
over time becomes sort of the legacy
business is not going to go away. You
can still go out and write and mail a
paper check in the mail if you want to.
Like you could get out a checkbook and
send someone a check. And the whole
thing I mean I somebody asked like we
were buying a house and I had to find a
check and I was like oh my god I like I
think I had to call the bank and be like
can you issue me any new checks? Um but
because who has that anymore?
>> I can't remember the last time I wrote a
check.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Right. You're like
where's my my checkbook? that I was like
uh and
you can still do that and banks it is
still going to be probably decades
before banks eliminate that capability
even though nobody uses it but you you
can't just mothball wallet so you have
to maintain these things that sort of
phase out as legacy modes of operation
but
what I one of the things I'm very much
focused on is
is thinking through
what when people operate onchain and
when people prefer a 24/7 onchain
experience, people who are used to
trading from their phone, who are used
to settling instantly, who are surprised
when they bought a mutual fund and the
money's not there for 3 days, they think
something went wrong and they're calling
in, right? Um, what do those people want
to invest in? But what's also weird is I
see the other way round, which is what
can I force down the throats of retail
investors by tokenizing because I've run
out of buyers for credit funds or
private credit and stuff like that,
right? And I worry there's a mismatch.
It's like I've never met a real estate
guy who has not said I'm interested in
tokenization.
But on the other side, I've never met a
retail investor who really cares about
buying tokens on a share of some illquid
building in wherever, but they're just
looking like they're, you know, they
just want to dump their assets into a
new market. So, we got to be careful. I
think the point being is who you
developing product for, why, and how.
There's real innovation, real
opportunity, but it's not just
tokenizing everything that exists.
No. And I I mean I do think that's
important. I mean I think people people
have since the dawn of time tried to
introduce liquidity into things where
there is no liquidity.
>> Yeah. We see that a lot every time.
Every time in fact it blows up in the
end.
>> Yes. And it just can't be done. I think
um there is that question of like oh
well this is you know this is how we
reach these like additional marginal
retail investors who want who want juicy
yield. um and we put it in a tokenized
format and it and one of two things
happens.
You either don't change the underlying
terms and conditions of what is a
non-marketable fund, i.e. like it's a
quarterly or monthly redemption and
there's a gating and that is how those
funds work and that's how they should
work and that's how they're able to
generate the returns they do. It is that
sticky capital structure. Um
>> and you can put that in a smart
contract. you you totally can but
then people need to understand that that
that is what they are getting. just
because it it came on a blockchain
doesn't mean that it changes the
underlying or what's even more
concerning is people will buy that right
um and structure it in such a way that
they are packaging the economic interest
right and they are essentially trying to
create a secondary market
where you don't have an abstract every
day where you don't know what the
underlying value is um and I think I
think we'll see that doesn't end Well,
especially when you introduce right like
infinite looping then it becomes like a
real powder keg. Um but you are going to
wind up this is like where people
introduce counterparty risk that and
take on counterparty risk that they
don't know about or don't understand.
Um, and
the piece that I think is really
interesting is if you talk to a
portfolio manager at a private equity
fund or an alternatives fund, they do
not want their stuff to mark to market
daily like this.
>> No, right. Like that's the whole it's a
big part of what they do.
>> That's right. It is to have a zero
volatility structure
>> with things that actually volatile
underneath is
>> is the arbitrage. It's
>> Exactly. And then they don't want to
send an investor letter to like every
guy who held the token for 30 seconds
one day. I mean they don't like right
like you get an investor letter is like
stamped to you. Like they are very
protective of that intellectual property
of the underlying like of of what their
activity is which is not nefarious. It's
how it's how that type of investment
works. Um and so I wonder if we at some
point see push back from the actual PMs
themselves. Um but you you just can't
safely introduce liquidity where it
doesn't exist.
>> No. But anything with liquidity,
anything fixed income related that's
relatively liquid, you know, yield
products, fantastic. You know, a lot of
those products are going to be better
than as you said the looped um you know
yield farming products that are on DeFi.
And people can then have a choice about
where they get yield from, what the risk
factor is. All of equities, anything
basically homogeneous should be on
chain. It's the fastest most efficient
way of transferring and custodying
assets, you know, all of that should
come. Um, but we don't have to tokenize
illquid real estate um as the first
thing.
>> Yeah. And it's funny because still when
you see like still oftentimes people say
um oh well like one of the main sort of
compelling arguments for tokenization it
brings like it brings greater
accessibility and liquidity to illquid
asset classes and it was like well it
brings greater accessibility and the
illusion of greater liquidity but it it
doesn't actually create liquidity where
there is none right
>> and are you finding that there are now
institutional clients who will take
tokenized stuff so you know Like, you
know, I talked to Sandy Call a lot.
She's a good friend at Franklin. And,
you know, it takes a while because you
you tokenize some yield products and now
you've got to get your customers to
actually buy it because they're they're
not retailled. They're institutionalled.
So, they have to then build the crypto
rails to actually get used to this
stuff. I mean, everyone's doing it, but
it's slow, right?
>> It is slow. Um, it is slow and it's a
lot of education, right? Um when you
think about sort of the the due
diligence rubric that that any of those
sort of especially at the institutional
level any of those firms would go
through um it's a big lift. Um one of
the things that I have found really
interesting is I want to say over the
past six months I have probably done 15
or 20 board presentations
on tokenization and stable coins. So
what kind of companies
>> like very like our large institutional
um our large institutional clients. So
we have a a very very big part of it. So
we're $1.8 trillion asset manager. A
large portion our retirement assets
where we you know people have 401ks and
we administer the retirement program.
Um, and what is happening is that these
companies, their boards are like hearing
about tokenization and like it's become
like a buzz word and they're sort of not
really sure what it means and they want
to get up to speed. Um, and there has
been a real movement for different and
it it's they're it's all independent of
each other. It's been like one sort of
inbound, hey, this somebody from a board
called and they want to know if you can
come do a teaching on tokenization.
Um, and I have been surprised by
how much the sort of pace picked up very
very quickly. Like I was I had never
been asked to do it six months ago was
asked the first time and then it's just
like
>> I I imagine that the treasury operations
of large corporations are also I mean
I've I spoke to I don't know a whole
bunch of them in the past and they were
starting to get interested in in this
and the other people who were so obvious
to me and it's not really happened yet
is the massive commodity trading firms
because they have assets tied up in
Angola to Tanzania to to you know French
New Guinea all sorts of places and
they've got council controls to get
around. They got vast amounts of money
slloshing around and they might as well
just have an internal stable coin rails
and they can move money around from
entity to entity no problem. And I'm
surprised that's not happened at scale
yet.
>> I that one does surprise me as well.
>> Brazil has Brazil has started doing it.
>> Brazil is actually unbelievably crypto
forward. Yeah,
>> like I mean it doesn't get it does not
get enough um credit but incredibly
crypto forward. Um but I I actually have
um I have a friend who's a head trader
for LAM for one of the like very big
commodities firms. Um, and he he's in a
trading role obviously and and a few
different times I've been like why
aren't you guys using like I what is the
rationale? Like are you guys having
conversations about it? Like are you
like are you thinking about it but you
just haven't gotten there or and and
he's like nope nope we're not nobody's
looking at it. Um
>> well while Louis while Louis Drafus
and a bunch of the soft commodity houses
have did it in 20
17 they basically or 16 they basically
use smart contracts now for all the
letters of credit the shipping the whole
lot. So they can move this stuff around
really fast but it's not taken off
elsewhere yet. It's bizarre.
>> Yeah. Um there was actually like a I
don't know if you remember there was a
really interesting
>> it was city it was city and it was um
trade financing
>> and they had the smart contract
triggered by I'm going to forget which
canal but
whatever canal it was um they like it
was triggered by the GPS like
essentially like the the oracle brought
in that um the ship had passed through
the canal based on like the GPS reading
so that was like the verification and
then the trade financing was released.
And to me, um
especially
especially when you have um
multi-jurisdictional pieces
uh and the cost of capital is so high
internally as a result.
I I don't understand why there hasn't
been greater adoption there. In my
previous life as an equity derivative
salesman early in my career, Cargill
were one of our clients because they run
this huge balance sheet and they have so
much excess capital. And one of the
things they were doing was doing
something in South Africa and they get
stuck with rand that they couldn't move
at the time. There was the dual rand
system, the financial run, the
commercial. And so we used to do the
index arb for them because they would be
stuck with this capital and it was a way
of getting capital out. All of these
things they have to do. And like all of
this could just go so quickly now.
>> I know. And um yeah, I mean like you
look at historically like Argentina with
the blue ship swap raid, the same thing.
Yeah, it's um
it is interesting. I mean it
>> I don't know why more firms haven't
adopted it as a really effective
internal cash management tool. And I
I wonder if it's more so I wonder if
it's more so that the people who are
typically in those roles are not their
coverage from like Southside Banks is
just not in a position yet to be
pitching those as products. Like there's
not there's not an opportunity there
that they can capitalize.
>> There's always somebody being paid to
therefore recycle the capital in a
different way. So there's somebody
making the money out of this arbitrage
in South Africa or you know so I mean
they're very smart people as we know
they figure out how to get their cost of
capital down as low as possible. So
there's a bunch of people's jobs that
don't want that to happen I guess as
well.
>> Yes. Exactly right. So I mean they'll be
cannibalizing their own their own
business. Um but yeah it's you know it's
usually your especially when you have a
huge like multi- so you know
multinational global sort of
conglomerate that does something that
operates across so many different you
know 20 different currencies and um they
have enormous sellside relation like
bank relationships um and those are the
people who are you know sort of
constantly coming through the door
pitching them on cash management and all
of the tools and I think that maybe it
may be the case that stable coins are
not in that arsenal that
>> well because you make more money selling
currency options.
>> Of course.
>> Exactly.
>> Of course. So, so if you're watching
from a large global multinational
company, please call us and we will
we'll do a walkthrough on why you should
be doing this with uh open interoperable
stable coins and you're going to save a
ton of money and time.
>> Blue, listen, fabulous conversation.
Really enjoyed it. I think we could have
talked a lot longer, but um but let's
see where this goes. It would be nice to
get a bit of liquidity back in crypto
because I think we've all taken our
penants for getting over excited um
earlier as you said and uh maybe it's
our time again soon.
>> I think so. I think so. Um thank you so
much for having me. It was such a a
pleasure to talk today. So
>> yeah, fantastic. We'll get you back on
at some point and catch up with where
you are.
>> Oh, sounds good.
>> What I love about somebody like Blue is
this commonality of language of
understanding. She's lived through the
emerging market crisis. She understands
the lens with which to look through
crypto. It's volatile. It's nasonent.
It's an emerging market itself. It's a
frontier market. And so once you use
that lens, you understand it better. But
she's really understands the space
itself and also where it should go,
where it's going. She shares the
frustrations and also the joy of seeing
where it is today. But I really enjoy
these conversations. I hope you did,
too. And I'll see you next time. So, you
obviously like this video enough that
you've got to the end. That's quite a
big task. But listen, do me a favor. Hit
the like and subscribe button and also
check out what videos next cuz I think
you'll love it. But if you want even
more, and when I'm talking more, I'm
talking about memberergenerated ideas,
incredible alpha research, everything
there to help you in your journey, just
head to realton.com/join
for the best financial intelligence out
there and the pure alpha that's within
the platform.